<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jeff Krol Music - Music</title><link href="https://jeffkrol.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://jeffkrol.com/feeds/music.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://jeffkrol.com/</id><updated>2020-08-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Quartet Recording</title><link href="https://jeffkrol.com/quartet-recording.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-08-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jeff Krol</name></author><id>tag:jeffkrol.com,2020-08-01:/quartet-recording.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This first recording was another colaboative effort between my brother Matt and I in regards to the recording, the music however was put together by myself and it features some of my earlier compositions as well as some standards. I am joined by Ethan Helm on alto saxophone, Christian Li …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This first recording was another colaboative effort between my brother Matt and I in regards to the recording, the music however was put together by myself and it features some of my earlier compositions as well as some standards. I am joined by Ethan Helm on alto saxophone, Christian Li on keyboard and synth, and Matt on bass.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me the highlight of this session is the track "Mulder". The composition is a single line melody with no written harmony and we had never played it before, I'm pretty sure Ethan was transposing the sheet on the spot. The melody fuctions as a starting point for the completely free improviation afterwards, some nice moments happened and the take ended up having a very distinct vibe that still inspires me when I listen back from time to time. Maybe I'll dabble in writing some poetry in the future if I muster up the courage.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 340px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1317190577/size=large/bgcol=333333/linkcol=0f91ff/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://jeffkrol.bandcamp.com/album/session-1-15-2017"&gt;Session - 1/15/2017 by Jeff Krol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="Music"></category><category term="Quartet Recordings"></category></entry><entry><title>The Killtet</title><link href="https://jeffkrol.com/the-killtet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jeff Krol</name></author><id>tag:jeffkrol.com,2020-07-31:/the-killtet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Killtet was a group formed my brother Matt and I while we were living in Rochester, New York during the year and a half after we graduated from The Eastman School of Music in 2013. The group features myself on drums, Matt on bass, Colin Gordon on alto saxophone …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Killtet was a group formed my brother Matt and I while we were living in Rochester, New York during the year and a half after we graduated from The Eastman School of Music in 2013. The group features myself on drums, Matt on bass, Colin Gordon on alto saxophone, and Wills Mckenna on tenor saxophone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a group, we had a unique synergy that alowed us to explore our creativity in a highly improvised musical setting. This was in part due to the instrumentation being only monophonic instruments, but primaraly due to the friendship and comradery we shared along with a spark of reckless abandonment that made us feel like we could make any of our ideas work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These first two recordings were singles we recorded in the early stages of the group. The recording quality is unique, not a very natural sound, but the energy of the perforance and overall vibe of the band is clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=2821203617/size=large/bgcol=333333/linkcol=0f91ff/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://thekilltet.bandcamp.com/track/the-killzone"&gt;The Killzone by The Killtet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/track=3537383249/size=large/bgcol=333333/linkcol=0f91ff/tracklist=false/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://thekilltet.bandcamp.com/track/static"&gt;Static by The Killtet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last recording was from our last show at local music store and venue, Bernunzio's, in downtown Rochester. This is %100 low-fi, but the recording captures the essense of what we were trying to acheive. High energy, communicative, spontanious, and just a little reckless at times is how a recall the perforance after years past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 307px;" src="https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=2183408281/size=large/bgcol=333333/linkcol=0f91ff/artwork=small/transparent=true/" seamless&gt;&lt;a href="http://thekilltet.bandcamp.com/album/live-at-bernunzios"&gt;Live at Bernunzio&amp;#39;s by The Killtet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="Music"></category><category term="Killtet"></category></entry><entry><title>Trio Killzone</title><link href="https://jeffkrol.com/trio-killzone.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-07-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Jeff Krol</name></author><id>tag:jeffkrol.com,2020-07-29:/trio-killzone.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Trio Killzone was the predecessor of The Killtet, essentialy the same band minus Colin. During this time (2013-2014) I was diving deep into the free jazz movement of the 60's as well as more modern free musicians such as Tim Berne, Paul Motion, Tony Malaby, ext... What appealed to me …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Trio Killzone was the predecessor of The Killtet, essentialy the same band minus Colin. During this time (2013-2014) I was diving deep into the free jazz movement of the 60's as well as more modern free musicians such as Tim Berne, Paul Motion, Tony Malaby, ext... What appealed to me the most about these musicians, particularly the musicians of the 60's, were the pure ideological and philosophical ideas behind their music. To me, it really felt like they were searching for new ways to create music as oppose to just playing slick new licks and patterns that have the illusion of sounding fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give a more context, my brother Matt and I were first dabbling in recording technology at this time and this was one of the first recording we did together. It was a colaboratory effort bacause neither of us could afford all the gear on our own. We were in Matts apartment building which sported practice rooms for musicians and we were all in separate rooms so we couldn't see each other. I personaly felt bad about the recordings in the moment, I felt sloppy, thought the drums were going to sound like shit since I was in a tiny room, and didn't feel like the music went the way it should. Kind of an immature way to think since we were trying to play freely, but I learned a lot from the experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first recording is a little rough, but as a group were trying to play in a way that was purely spontaneous and as an added chalange we were trying to play in that way over a standard tune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/187173351&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;div style="font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/matt-krol" title="Matt Krol" target="_blank" style="color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;"&gt;Matt Krol&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/matt-krol/trio-killzone-i-hear-a-rhapsody" title="Trio Killzone - I Hear a Rhapsody" target="_blank" style="color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;"&gt;Trio Killzone - I Hear a Rhapsody&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This second recording was the highlight of the day, it was spontanious and free, yet organized and has a clear composition like structure. The only parameter we decided on was to start in a specific key, Bb major, not that the specific key mattern to me per se. Again, I thought this was going to sound bad but after the dust settled and I listened back it was clear that the moment we captured was something special. I'm not sure how it turned out so well since I am recalling this in hindsight, but maybe I was to a point of frustration that I had given up trying to sound like how I wanted and just played. I guess thats one way of getting there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/172937103&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;div style="font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/matt-krol" title="Matt Krol" target="_blank" style="color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;"&gt;Matt Krol&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/matt-krol/trio-killzone-free-improvisation" title="Trio Killzone - Free Improvisation" target="_blank" style="color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;"&gt;Trio Killzone - Free Improvisation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Music"></category><category term="Trio Killzone"></category></entry></feed>